准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
闯祸魔法棒
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
大法师的
魔法小屋
今晚
快来  珊迪
Come on, Sandy
你一定会爱上魔法小屋的
you'll love the Magic Shack
保证可以让你目瞪口呆
I guarantee you'll be astounded and amazed
都跟你说过了  海绵宝宝
I told ya, SpongeBob
我才不去看什么骗人的魔法表演
I ain't going to no phony hocus-pocus show
我可是专攻科学的松鼠
I'm a science squirrel
不相信魔法
I don't believe in magic
可大家命中都需要一丢丢魔法啊
But everyone needs a widdle magic in their "wives"
好吧  去就去
Alright, I'll go
不过我连一丢丢都不喜欢
But I'm not gonna wike it
现在  准备好目瞪口呆吧
And now, prepare to be astonished and stupefied
来观赏神秘魔法  表演者就是
by the mysterious magic of
大法师豪迪尼
the Great Howdini
豪家伙  他怎么做到的
"Howdini" do that?
闪光纸
Flash paper
都老掉牙的魔术了
Oldest trick in the book
豪家伙  他怎么做到的
"Howdini" do that?
牌都用胶水粘在一起了
The cards are glued together
豪家伙  他怎么做到的
"Howdini" do that?
用镜子和烟雾投影出来的障眼法
He's doing it all with smoke and mirrors
好
Okay
我们都懂
We get it
珊迪
Sandy?
豪家伙  他怎么做到的
"Howdini" do that?
我是全能的豪迪尼
I am the all-powerful Howdini
T恤衫可以前往大堂购买
T-shirts can be purchased in the lobby
演完魔法之后
我想不出任何有逻辑的解释
I can't come up with any logical explanation
来说明他怎么表演的
for how he did that
根本就是违反了科学原理
It goes against science
魔法是没法解释的  珊迪
You can't explain magic, Sandy
豪迪尼先生  可以给我签名吗
Mr. Howdini, can I have an autograph?
我很愿意
I'd be delighted
我也会表演魔法
I can do a magic trick too
业余
Amateur
拿着我的魔法棒
Hold my wand
可以签在我的背上吗
Can you sign my back?
这就签  我的小不点朋友
Here you go, my little friend
你的笔
Your pen
谢谢
Thank you
我来捡
I'll get it
谢谢
Thank you
吊威亚
Wires?
不对
No
全息投影
Holograms?
不对
No
催眠术
Hypnosis?
有可能
Maybe
珊迪啊  魔法本来就不合逻辑
Oh, Sandy, magic isn't logical
再见
See ya later
我得回家喂小蜗了
I gotta go home and feed Gary
什么
What?
好吧  再见
Oh yeah, see ya
在魔法小屋那边吃太多爆米花了
Too much Magic Shack popcorn
我都跟你说多少遍了
How many times have I told you
跟你说过不要做的事情不要做
not to do what I told you not to do?
冰淇淋
跟你说过不要做了  你却又不听
I told you not to, but you did not listen
非做跟你说过不要做的事情
and you did the thing that I told you not to do
搞得像我没跟你说过不要做
as if I never told you not to do it
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
听不见  我在喷杀虫剂
Can't hear you, spraying bugs
小蜗
Gare-bear
今天过得好充实
What a day
我看了大法师豪迪尼演了特神的表演
I saw Howdini the Great do amazing things
珊迪却不相信魔法
And Sandy didn't believe in magic
不过豪迪尼让她漂浮在舞台上空
but Howdini made her float up on stage
搞得珊迪现在都动摇了
and now she's not so sure of herself
小蜗  你趁我不在重新装修了客厅吗
Gary, did you redecorate the living room while I was out?
我喜欢
I love it
我就不废话了  来喂你吧
Of course I'll quit my jabbering and feed you
腐烂的植物
Rotting vegetation
你最爱的口味
Your favorite flavor
用餐愉快
Bon appetit
小蜗
Gary
你干嘛吃台球
Why are you eating billiard balls?
不过更严重的问题应该是
But I guess the bigger question is
我干嘛要喂你吃台球
why did I feed you billiard balls?
助步器老头
Old Man Walker?
你来这干嘛
What are you doing here?
小蜗呢
And where's Gary?
你就是小蜗吗
You're Gary?
不可能
That's impossible
如果你是小蜗  那就告诉我
If you're Gary, then tell me something
只有真正的小蜗才知道的事
only the real Gary would know
我睡觉还真会打嗝
I do belch in my sleep
小蜗  真的是你
Gary, it is you
小蜗  我好像出现幻觉了
Gary, I think I'm seeing things
我在豪迪尼的魔法表演肯定是出事了
Something must have happened to me
at Howdini's magic show
好办法  小蜗
Good thinking, Gary
我马上就去看急诊
I'll go to the emergency room right now
小蜗
别忘了
Don't forget to
你懂的
Well, you know
看到你的病情所在了
I see your trouble
你的身体里有一根魔法棒
There's a magic wand inside you
而你又频繁打嗝  就触发了它
And your hiccups are setting it off
我一定是把豪迪尼的魔法棒
I must have mixed up Howdini's wand
误认成我的签字笔了
with my autograph pen
让我伸手进去  帮你掏出魔法棒
Well, let me just dig in there and get that wand for ya
那要不然就治好你的打嗝吧
What if we just cure your hiccups instead?
我给你打点水
I'll get you some water
这样应该就能治好了
That'll fix it
谢了  医生
Thanks, Doc
我不打嗝了
My hiccups are gone
急诊
我不需要医生  我需要珊迪
I don't need a doctor, I need a Sandy
对
Yup
魔法棒就在里面
There's the wand
我要分析一下那玩意
I want to analyze that thing
看它怎么变的魔法
and see how it makes magic
摇一摇就能掉出来了
It'll come loose if I give it a good shake
别
No
别  珊迪
No, Sandy
不要
No
对  我忘记说了
Yeah, I forgot to say
摇一下就会触发魔法
The shaking is what triggers the magic
幸好知道了
Good to know
这种能施魔法的玩意一定得轻拿轻放
We gotta handle this enchanted doohickey
real delicate-like
抱歉
Sorry
可恶
Aw, dang
魔法师来了
It's the magician
天啊  他见到我们的样子好像很开心
Boy, does he look happy to see us
你怎么发现我们的
How'd you find us?
难道是用心灵感应发现的
With your telepathic powers?
不对
No
我的魔法棒有定位
My wand has GPS
可悲的笔还给你
Here's your pathetic pen
把魔法棒还给我
Now give me back my wand
你已经玩够了
You've had your fun
那就是问题所在  豪弟弟
That's the problem, Howdooya
你的魔法棒卡在我朋友身体里了
Your wand is stuck in my friend here
摇都摇不出来
and we can't shake it out
我这就把它弄出来
I'll get it out
就算要撕碎他也在所不辞
Even If I have to tear him apart
我来救你了  魔法棒
I'm coming to save you, Wanda
我就感觉这家伙疯了
I had a feeling this guy was nuts
我要像切牌一样切了你
I'll cut you like a deck of cards
不许伤害我朋友
Don't hurt my friend
珊迪  你在干什么
Sandy, what are you doing?
你就是我的魔法棒  海绵宝宝
You're my magic wand, SpongeBob
可恶
Dagnabbit
魔法烂透了
Magic stinks
吃我一魔法  吸血鬼德古拉
Eat magic, Dracula
我一直都很想戴耳环
I've always wanted earrings
飞吧  我的蛤蜊们
Fly, my clammies
飞吧
Fly
这简直是异想天开
This is a stretch of the imagination
拉
但我还是相信这一切
but I'm a believer
谢谢  珊迪
Thank you, Sandy
我得处理一两件事
I gotta take care of a couple of things
我想到要怎么取出
I just figured out how to get
你身体里的魔法棒了  海绵宝宝
the magic wand out of you, SpongeBob
那就是科学
Science
大泡弹汽水
Fizz Bomb Soda
打个大爆嗝
Burp Explosion
摇动汽水  就会释放出二氧化碳
The agitation of the soda releases carbon dioxide
把魔法棒逼出你的身体
which will force the wand out of your body
这下再也不往身上的洞里放东西了
That'll teach me not to put stuff in my pores
豪弟弟  我会把你变回来
Alright, Howdooya, I'll turn you back
但条件是你给我安分点
but only if you play nice
我从前一直不相信科学
I've never believed in science
直到我看到了那套汽水变气球的戏法
until I saw that soda and balloon trick
好家伙  珊迪怎么做到的
"How-Sandy" do that?
也没什么
That's nothing
我八年级科学课就学会那套戏法了
I learned that trick in 8th grade science class
能不能再多给我介绍下这个科学
Can you tell me more about this "science"?
来我实验室一趟吧
Come on in to my lab
我来给你展示一些实验
I'll show you some experiments
保证惊到你山羊胡都在转
that'll make your goatee spin
给你吧  海绵宝宝
Here you go, SpongeBob
都有科学了  还要什么魔法
Who needs magic when you have science
过度迷信
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
啊  我们回到了蟹老板的海军生涯
Ah, here we are, back in Mr. Krabs' old navy days
海军生涯
这是年轻时的蟹老板
And here is the young Mr. Krabs
践行着海军的荣耀
exercising the Navy's honor
勇气  与奉献精神
courage, and commitment
而践行方式是给甲板拖地
by swabbing the deck
小心点  拖地的
Careful there, swabbie
从梯子底下走过去会倒霉的
It's bad luck to walk under a ladder
尤其是在十三号星期五这天
Especially on Friday the 13th
我才不迷那个破信呢
I ain't stupor-stitious
看看我好了
Just watch me
看吧
See?
没事
Nothing
完全是无稽之谈
All balderdash
快看啊
And looky here
爬过了只黑蜗牛呢
A black snail just crossed me path
没事
Nothing
第二次
Again
啥都没
Zilch
你这是在玩命  水手
You're tempting fate, sailor
还有什么无脑迷信呢
What's another stupid-stition?
对了
Oh, yeah
打碎镜子
Breaking a mirror
清晨天空红  水手敲警钟
Red sky in morning, sailor take warning
什么
Wha?
早说了吧
I told ya so
十三号星期五
Friday the 13th
今天是十三号星期五
Today's Friday the 13th
今天最好小心点
I best be careful today
马蹄铁朝下
Horseshoe facing down
厄运
Bad luck
好多了
That's better
不好
Oh no
开始了
It's starting
等一下
Wait a minute
看到别针不去捡
See a pin, let it lay
好运全部都不见
and all good luck will pass away
不好
Oh no
蟹堡王
屋里打伞  厄运泛滥
Umbrella open inside, bad luck is on the tide
那水管往我脑袋滴了我一早上的水
That pipe's been dripping on my head all morning
我又能怎么办啊
What am I supposed to do?
就当免费洗了个澡吧
Just enjoy the free shower
鞋子放桌上  运气不稳当
Shoes on the table, your luck be unstable
不好意思
Excuse me?
你疯了吗
Are you nuts?
不行不行不行
Oh, no, no, no, no, no
屋里吹口哨  运气都跑掉
An indoor whistle brings luck's dismissal
这到底是在闹什么啊
What's the commotion in the ocean?
今天是十三号星期五
It's Friday the 13th
蟹老板一年比一年迷信
and Mr. Krabs gets more superstitious every year
你不会是先迈左脚进蟹堡王的吧
You didn't enter me restaurant
with your left foot, did ya?
口袋里有水煮蛋吗
Any boiled eggs in your pockets?
有墓地里的石头吗
Stones from a cemetery?
有干制鱼首级吗
Shrunken fish heads?
[ 干制首级：将战争中砍下的头
干缩当作战利品保存，有时用于祭祀 ]
好  没有违禁品
Okay, you're clean
慢着
Hold it
这是什么
What's this?
[ 此为前述的干制首级 ]
出去
Get out
兄弟  你要不是厄运缠身
Pal, if it weren't for bad luck
根本连运气都没有
you'd have no luck at all
头号老板
蟹老板好
Ahoy, Mr. Krabs
你的早茶马上就来
Your morning cup of tea, coming right up
用小刀搅拌  就是挑争端
Stir with a knife, you'll stir up strife
邪眼出现
The evil eye
有人升天
Someone will die
你那领带哪来的
Where'd you get that tie?
这个旧领带吗
This old tie?
之前是我曾曾爷爷的
It belonged to my great-great grandfather
死人领带  末日要来
Dead man's tie, the end is nigh
我还没死呢
I'm not dead yet
曾曾爷爷好
Hi, Great-Great Grandpa
领带还你
Here's your tie back
海绵可以活两百年呢
Sponges can live up to 200 years
老螃蟹要是别老想那个破迷信
Maybe Krabs would have time to fix this leaky pipe
估计就有空来修这个漏水的水管了
if he didn't obsess over dumb superstitions
想把事办成
If you want something done
就得亲自动手
then do it yourself
冷静点  老螃蟹
Get a hold of yourself, Krabs
不要玩命
Don't tempt fate
熬过今天就好了
Just make it through the day
你怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
走后门啊
The back door
等一下
Wait
我办公室没后门
There is no back door to my office
那也是厄运吗
Is that also bad luck?
一定是
It must be
你是厄运吗
Are you bad luck?
我是厄运吗
Am I bad luck?
我们两个凑在一起就是厄运吗
Are we both bad luck together?
切
Oh, poo
你刚刚对我切什么
Did you just "poo" me?
不能把自己反锁在办公室里一辈子
You can't stay locked up in your office forever
蟹堡王还需要经营呢
The Krusty Krab needs managing
看来你说得对
I suppose you're right
我多半是太过大惊小怪了吧
I'm probably getting all worked up over nothing
看来一切安全
Looks like the coast is clear
小心那个水坑
Watch out for that puddle
小心什么
Watch out for wha
梯子
Ladder?
又一只黑蜗牛
Another black snail?
打翻的盐
Spilled salt?
他还有呼吸吗
Is he breathing?
我看不出来
I can't tell
他冒了一口气
There's his breath
有呼吸
He's breathing
碎镜子
Broken mirror?
不好
Oh no
又要发生了
It's happening again
我在海军生涯里没出过这种事
Well, that didn't happen in me old navy days
是一只小妖精
It's a leprechaun
不对
No
那是小妖粗
It's a lepre-can't
反向版的小妖精
A reverse leprechaun
它们是厄运的化身
They're bad luck personified
就说了吧
I told you so
祝你们早上倒
Bottom of the morning to ya
怎么了
'Smatter?
被蜗牛咬到舌头了吗
Snail got your tongues?
干嘛光站那  跟木头做的一样
Why are ye just standing there like you're made of wood?
很好
Very well
你们都是木头做的
You're all made of wood
吓得我呆若木鸡
Shiver me timbers
我们都变木头了
We're all timbers
该怎么办
What do we do?
要用幸运抵消厄运
We need to counteract the bad luck with some good luck
要是能找到就好了
It would be great if we could find some
敲木头会有好运
Knock on wood
对了  小子
That's it, boy-o
跟着我做
Follow me
大家敲木头
Everyone knock on wood
我头快裂开了
Me splittin' cranium
快看
Look
有彩虹
A rainbow
原来是真的
So it's true
彩虹尽头有装满黄金的罐子
There are pots of gold at the end of rainbows
拿到黄金我就能发财了
I could be rich with all that gold
拿到黄金我就能辞职了
I could quit my job with all that gold
拿到黄金就能用它在地上写我名字了
I could spell my name out on the floor with all that gold
等等
Wait
不行
Nix
别碰那个罐子
Stay away from that pot
四叶草
Four-leaf clovers?
兔脚
Rabbits' feet?
黄金呢
What happened to the gold?
马蹄铁
Horseshoes?
许愿骨
Wishbones?
这些都是幸运符
These are all lucky charms
幸运蛋糕
A lucky cake
猜猜谁现在可以许愿了呢
And guess who gets to make a wish now
把那些东西放回去
Put those things back
你们都不准碰
You mustn't touch them
抱歉
Sorry
还给你
Here ya go
不行
No
我突然感觉很幸运
All of a sudden, I'm feeling lucky
不行
Nay
住手
Cease
别
Don't
拜托
Please
小妖粗变成了小妖精
The lepre-can't just turned into a lepre-can
准确来说是变回才对
Turned back into, to be precise
几十年前  有个老海巫婆
'Twas decades ago that an old sea witch
把我变成了小妖粗
turned me into a lepre-can't
不过多亏了你们  我又复原了
But thanks to you, I'm restored
能变回带来幸运的绿模样  太美妙了
'Tis grand to be me old green, good-luck self again
多谢先生们
Thank thee, gentlemen
从头到脚  恢复肉身多完好
Return to meats from your heads to your feets
我又伸缩自如了
I'm porous again
如果我没记错那些上古传说
Now if I remember the old legends correctly
要是抓到小妖精
if you catch a leprechaun
那小妖精就得把他那罐黄金送出去
he's got to give you his pot of gold
得了吧
Oh, please
你不会相信那通废话吧
You don't believe all that malarkey, do ya?
我今天信了不少呢
I've believed a lot today
先抓到我再说
You gotta catch me first
在找一罐黄金吗
Looking for a pot of gold?
抓住他
Get him
等等
Wait
知道我最喜欢彩虹的什么特点吗
Do you know the one thing I love most about rainbows?
什么
What?
彩虹很漂亮吗
They're pretty?
错
No
彩虹不会永存
They don't last forever
黑蜗牛
Black snail